Ordinary Family. Extraordinary Story.
The Castle is a drama, comedy film directed by Rob Sitch.
The quirky Kerrigan family lives together in a makeshift home they built themselves – with great pride and a bizarre
attention to detail – a few yards from the edge of Melbourne, Australia's busy Tullamarine Airport.
When a building inspector condemns the building and reveals that the government plans to use their land for an airport expansion,
Darryl Kerrigan and his brood recruit hack attorney Dennis Denuto and prepare themselves for the fight of their lives.
Darryl Kerrigan, played by Michael Caton.
Sal Kerrigan, played by Anne Tenney.
Dale Kerrigan, played by Stephen Curry.
Steve Kerrigan, played by Anthony Simcoe.
Tracy Kerrigan, played by Sophie Lee.
Wayne Kerrigan, played by Wayne Hope.
The Castle is a 1997 Australian comedy film directed by Rob Sitch, and written by Rob Sitch, Santo Cilauro, Tom Gleisner and Jane
Kennedy of Working Dog Productions, all veteran writers and performers on ABC's The Late Show and The D-Generation.
The film stars Michael Caton, Anne Tenney, Stephen Curry, Anthony Simcoe, Sophie Lee and Wayne Hope as the Kerrigan family, as well as Tiriel Mora, Robyn
Nevin, Eric Bana, Costas Kilias and long time collaborator Charles "Bud" Tingwell (who had worked with the team since 1993 on "The Late Show").
The film's title is based upon the English saying, repeatedly
referred to in the film, "A man's Home is his Castle.".
Its humour plays on the national self-image, most notably the concept of
working-class Australians and their place in modern Australia.
Shot in 11 days on a budget of approximately A$750,000, The Castle gained widespread acclaim in
Australia, where it is considered one of the greatest Australian films ever made.
It grossed A$10,326,428 at the box office in Australia.
The film explores themes of underdog, australia, airport, court case, court.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.